I'm not...
我一点都
Mom.
妈
There you are.
妈来了
And you are?
您是
Meng'an's elder sister.
这是梦安的大姑姐
We met at the wedding.
结婚的时候咱们见过
Li Jing.
李静姐
Yeah.
对对对
He has a very good memory.
我儿子记性特别好
The people he met
他见过的人啊
never forget.
过目不忘
Yeah.
是是是
Have a seat.
姐 您坐坐坐
Sit here.
来 坐这儿
Please.
来
Just
那个
a gift.
小礼物
Thank you.
谢谢 谢谢 谢谢
Mengxin.
心心
I came to see you.
姐来看你来了
It's hard for you.
这是遭了多大的罪啊
You suffered.
受了多少苦啊
You are
你看这小脸
very fair.
本来就白
But you're pale now.
现在就变成惨白了
Meng'an told me about caesarean section.
梦安跟我说你剖腹产了
So I came to see you right away.
我马上就来看你了
Are you still in pain?
伤口还疼吗
Yeah.
疼
I can't even sleep.
疼得都睡不着觉
Have a good Postpartum Confinement.
你要好好坐月子啊
Take good care of yourself.
好好地保养自己
Thank you.
谢谢静姐
En...
那个
I bought a pair of
我 我给宝贝
gold bracelets for our baby.
买了一对金镯子
Put it on her
等她大一点
when she is older.
就给戴上
Just come.
姐 您说您来就来吧
You don't have to buy gifts.
还让您破费
Thank you.
真是不好意思啊
What about the kid?
孩子呢
In that thermostat.
在那个恒温室呢
Is she okay?
没事吧
Just observe her.
就是观察观察
Don't
这个孩子啊
worry about her.
倒是不用多操心
She is full of vitality.
她的生命力很旺盛
Just you.
就是你
Look.
你看
Oh, my god.
天哪
Your thin arms.
你看看这小胳膊
You are too thin.
你这也太瘦了
I'm telling you,
我跟你说啊
surgery will weaken
这女人 大小开个刀
a woman.
那都会伤元气的
Mengxin.
心
See what she means?
明白静姐的意思吗
Weaken you.
会伤元气
So you should eat and drink enough
所以要足吃足喝
to recover.
恢复元气
Yeah.
对
Well.
这样吧
I'll ask my husband
我让我们家老欧阳
to give you a prescription
给你开个
for tonifying blood and qi.
补血补气的方子
Once you
这个女人呢
recover,
气血一好
your milk
奶水就好
and meridians
奶水好
will get better.
经络就好
That's good
经络好
for you
大人也好
and your child.
孩子也好
Right?
是吧
Well.
姐 姐 姐 这样
Mom.
妈
This bracelet she bought
姐买的这个
must be very good.
肯定特漂亮的镯子
Let's go and have a look.
咱仨去看看去
You go ahead.
你去吧
Did she give milk?
那个 下奶了吗
No.
还没下来呢
That's no good.
那不行啊
She has to eat and drink more.
得多吃多喝
Pig trotter soup.
什么猪蹄子汤
Crucian carp soup. Millet porridge.
通草鲫鱼汤 小米粥
You have to drink more.
你就得多喝才能下奶呀
Write a prescription.
那你赶紧给开个方子
I'll make it for her.
然后我回家给她做
Jing.
静姐
We decided not to
我们这次决定了
breastfeed our child this time.
不给孩子吃母乳
That's bad for Mengxin.
对妈妈太折腾了
The nutrition
孩子现在的
of milk powder
婴儿营养配方奶粉
is particularly balanced.
营养特别均衡
You are ignorant.
愚昧
Why doesn't she breastfeed?
为什么不吃母乳啊
She has just given birth now.
她现在刚生完孩子
She is in the golden lactation period.
正是黄金哺乳期
The child must eat breast milk.
一定要吃母乳
That will make her
吃母乳的孩子
smarter
聪明
and healthier.
结实
She won't get sick easily
而且三岁以前
before she is three years old.
不容易得病
Now she
虽然现在她看着
suffers,
有一点遭罪
but it's good for the child.
但是对孩子好啊
Right?
是不是
Xiongxiong
那个熊熊是不是
ate breast milk, right?
也是吃母乳的
Yeah.
是啊
Until he was one year old.
当时熊熊吃到一岁哪
The second child must also breastfeed.
那老二也一定要吃母乳
It is good for Mengxin.
对心心是有好处的
Yeah.
对
Well.
这样吧
I'll
我呢
examine her.
来给她看看
I have studied massage.
我学过按摩
I know
对于经络疏通
meridian dredging.
是有一套的
Don't worry.
别着急
I'll do it.
我来
Mengxin.
心心
What are you doing?
你干什么
That's OK.
没事
I'll
我给你
clear your meridians.
经络疏通
Don't touch me.
你别碰我
Jing.
姐 姐 姐
Get out.
滚
Jing. Let's go out.
姐姐姐 咱们出去吧
Well.
这个 这个 这个
Middle-aged people should
中年人
learn to be happy with themselves.
要学会愉快地自洽
Take a back seat,
虽然退居二线
but
但
you can still
仍然可以给自己
inspire yourself.
画饼
You can
等你休完产假
make a comeback
还可以
after maternity leave.
东山再起
For example,
比如
a housewife
一个叫
named Chen Wanzhen
陈婉真的女士
can
家庭主妇
start
八年
from scratch
都可以
after eight years.
从头开始
As a
作为一个
working woman for twenty years,
二十年的职场女性
you
你
definitely can.
一定可以
No, no, no.
不不不
Not quite the same.
这 不太一样啊
Why?
怎么不一样了
You dislike me?
你嫌弃我啦
I didn't charge you for giving you
你让我给你做心理按摩
a psychological massage.
没跟你收费就不错了
You should learn from me.
你真应该学学我
Do you know what books
你知道我最近
I have read recently?
看什么书吗
Finance.
金融
I will retake my qualification license.
我准备重考执照
I want to go back to my old job.
干回老本行
Your execution ability is very strong.
你这执行能力可以啊
Sure.
那当然了
Here I am.
来喽
Who is it?
谁啊
Ms. Chen.
陈小姐
Hello, Dr. Yu.
俞医生 你好
The hospital
我院里面啊
gave us fruit.
发了点水果
Too much.
太多了
I can't finish it alone.
我一个人吃不了
I brought you a box of fruit.
给你拿了一箱
No need, I have it.
不用 不用 家里有
It's okay.
没事
Sure.
可以 可以 可以
Thank you.
谢谢啊
There is
那个
just no fruit.
家里头正好没有水果了
Nonsense.
谁说没有水果啊
No fruit can be squeezed.
没有能榨汁的水果了
Take it to juice.
那正好 拿去榨汁
Yeah.
是是是
Ms. Chen.
陈小姐
Have you been exercising recently?
你最近运动了吗
I have no time.
我最近没有时间
I'm running recently.
我不是去跑步吗
So I want to invite you.
我正好问你一下
You have hypoglycemia,
你不是低血糖
so you'd better exercise more.
最好多运动运动
That's good for your health.
对身体好
Thank you.
好的 谢谢啊
Why don't you go running?
要不你们去跑步吧
Let's go together.
那咱们一起吧
I can't.
我就不了
I'm leaving soon.
我马上就走了
Don't go.
走什么走呀
You haven't squeezed the juice yet.
这水果汁还没榨呢
You must be her neighbor.
你就是那个医生邻居吧
She talks about you a lot.
婉真老提起你
I didn't.
谁老提起他了
Please come in.
进来坐
No need.
不不 不了
I will go running.
我 我去跑步了
Well.
好嘞
Thank you, Dr. Yu.
谢谢啊 俞医生
Goodbye.
再见
Let's have dinner another day.
改天一起吃饭啊
OK.
好嘞 好
Well.
行了
What a nice guy.
多好的小伙子
Stop it.
好什么好
Invite him to dinner?
还请人家吃饭
You scared him away.
把人家吓跑了吧
No.
这怎么能叫吓跑了呢
I call it being polite.
这叫懂事
He has high emotional intelligence.
小伙子情商很高啊
Don't gossip
收起你那八卦的
with me.
小表情吧
Why not?
八卦怎么了
It works.
八卦有用啊
You just gave me
你看你刚才给我做什么
a psychological massage.
老半天的心理按摩
But it didn't work.
我都没什么用
I feel comfortable
小伙子一来
when he comes.
我现在身心舒畅
I am very happy now.
任督二脉都打通了
Let's change the subject.
换个话题
What?
换什么呀
Say something serious.
说点正经的
OK.
好嘞
I think
医生
the profession of doctor
我觉得这个职业
is good.
还是不错的
He is
小伙子样子
good-looking.
长得也还可以
He should have
三十多岁
some life experience in his thirties.
应该有一些生活阅历了
Before, you said that
之前你说
he was kind to children.
他对孩子也是不错的
How is he?
那人怎么样
Is he reliable?
到底靠谱吗
Stop it.
哪儿跟哪儿啊
Far from.
差远啦
Don't think too much.
你别多想好不好
I didn't. It's obvious.
我没多想 这很明显呀
En...
不是
What do you mean, far from?
差远了是什么意思
With whom?
你跟谁比啊
Yu Hai?
于海吗
Forget it.
于海就算了吧
You're going to remarry him?
你还打算跟他复婚吗
No.
没有 没有
You...
你
Don't look at me like that, okay?
你别这样看着我好吗
I really didn't.
我真没有
But you are happy now.
但是你现在很开心啊
I...
我
I finally got divorced.
我好不容易离了
I want to enjoy
我现在就想享受
my wonderful time alone now.
我一个人的美好时光
Is this not good?
这样不好吗
No.
好是好
What a pity.
这可惜了
En...
那
What a pity?
可惜啥呀
He's just a neighbor.
中国好邻居
Get to know each other better.
那就发展了他
Turn him into...
把他变成中国好
Well.
行了 行了
Squeeze juice for you.
给你榨果汁去
Dispel fire for you.
喝点流食祛祛火
Shut your mouth.
堵住你的嘴
Don't.
你别堵我嘴
He's good.
小伙子真不错
You go ahead.
不错 你去
I'm not divorced.
我没离呢
She is so cute.
真好玩
I was moved
看着这宝贝啊
by her.
这心都化了
I
我现在啊
hope Meng'an
就盼着梦安
has a child.
赶快也生一个胖宝宝
Don't worry.
梦安你别担心
She is the elder sister.
她有个大姐的样
Mengxin
倒是我们家心心啊
has a big temper now.
现在脾气很大
I can't stand her.
真是受不了
Everyone is willful in Confinement.
月子里都任性
We must understand her.
咱理解
Auntie.
大姨
You have worked hard.
你辛苦了啊
But for the sake of children,
但是为了孩子
we must be patient.
咱得忍
Yeah.
对
Prescription for milking.
那个下奶的方子
Rest assured.
你放心
I'll get it for you.
我给你弄
I mean,
我的意思呢
when Mengxin
等梦心呀
is in a better mood,
这个心情好一点
you advise her.
咱再给她做做工作
Yeah.
好 好
Be sure to let her breastfeed.
一定让她喂母乳
That's better.
还是母乳好
Yeah.
是啊
We didn't have
你说我们那时候
milk powder before.
也没有奶粉呢
We all breastfeed.
不都大家喂母乳吗
Young people nowadays are all delicate.
现在的孩子 都娇气
Dr. Li.
李大夫
The wound of Xu Mengxin
1201房许梦心产妇
in Room 1201 is cracked.
伤口裂开
Please come as soon as possible.
请您尽快过来一趟
Mr. Li.
李老师
Please have a look.
这您看一下
OK.
好嘞
Hello.
喂 姐
What do you want to eat tonight?
你晚上想吃什么呀
I'll cook for you.
姐给你做
No need.
别做了
Get ready-made ones.
买现成的吧
Meng'an may not come back
梦安今天晚上
for dinner tonight.
也不一定回来吃饭
She may have to
说不准的话
go to the hospital.
还得去趟医院
Which hospital?
去哪家医院了
Me?
你说我呀
I visited your
我去把你老丈人
father-in-law
还有小姨子
and sister-in-law.
都去探望了
We have to be polite.
咱礼数得到啊
You went to visit Mengxin?
你去医院看梦心了
Yeah.
对呀
She gave birth to a baby.
人家把孩子都生了
I have to go.
我不得去探个月子吗
I'm telling you,
我跟你说呀
she
你这小姨子
has a big temper.
脾气可大了
She's tough.
难缠
You don't have to go.
你探什么月子呀
You are not
这这 你这关系
that close to her.
也没那么近啊
I didn't even go.
我都没去
You are a man.
你一个男的
You needn't go.
探什么月子啊
She is
说到底
Meng'an's sister.
那不是梦安的妹妹吗
Since I'm here,
那我人都来了
I must be polite.
不得讲个礼数啊
Right?
是吧
Well.
行行行
I bought a pair of
我还给宝贝
gold bracelets for the child.
买了一对小金镯子
I tell you,
我跟你说啊
your brother-in-law
你妹夫
and his mother
跟你妹夫他妈
are very polite.
都挺讲礼数的
How's Mengxin?
那心心怎么样
The wound
好像
of her caesarean section
剖腹产的伤口
doesn't seem to be healing very well.
长得不太好
There is
今天又
something wrong with it today.
又出了点问题
No big problem.
问题不大
Jing.
姐
Do you have anything to do
你不会和这个问题
with it?
有关系吧
Nonsense.
你说什么呢
It has nothing to do with me.
这跟我有什么关系
I just care about her.
我关心还来不及呢
All right, I got to go.
行了 挂了吧
The doctor said
医生说了
the split wound was not serious.
伤口裂开不算严重
But the patient has a scar diathesis.
但患者有点疤痕体质
So for the next
所以接下来的
four to six hours,
四到六个小时
she must not move
千万不能乱动
to let the wound heal slowly.
让伤口慢慢愈合好
OK.
好好好
Sure.
肯定的
Thank you.
谢谢啊
Goodbye.
您慢走啊
Mengxin.
心
Honey.
老婆
Baby.
大宝贝
Don't talk.
别说话
Mengxin.
心
It's my fault.
都怪我 都怪我啊
It's all my fault.
真的怪我
I want to
我恨不得是我来
suffer for you.
替你受这罪
I'm really sorry about you.
我真对不住你 心
I'm sorry.
对不起
Honey. Honey. Honey.
老婆 老婆 老婆
Honey.
老婆
From now on,
从现在开始
I won't let anyone in.
我谁都不让他们进来
I'll let them all go out
把他们全轰出去
and leave you alone.
让你一个人静静地养
All.
全轰走
Except mom.
除了妈
Yeah.
对对对
My mom.
我妈
Your mother.
除了咱俩的你妈
Mengxin.
心
I will stand guard at the door
我到门口守着
and not let anyone in.
把他们全轰走
How about elder sister?
那姐呢
She must be let go.
轰走 必须让她走
I won't let her in.
不让她进来
Honey.
媳妇
Sleep well.
好好睡
Just stop, okay?
你们这没完没了的
Don't rush me.
催什么
My wife has just had surgery.
我老婆刚做完手术
Don't keep
你这这招魂的
pushing me.
你这一个一个的
Can't so many of you
那么多人
solve this little thing?
都弄不了这点破事
There you are.
姐来了
Haowen.
浩文
How's Mengxin?
心心怎么样了
She's asleep.
她睡了
What did the doctor say?
大夫怎么说的
Her wound is cracked
大夫说她伤口裂了
and she needs rest.
要静养
Has my elder sister been here?
我大姑姐是不是来了
Yeah.
对
She came to see Mengxin
她来看心心
and bought
还给孩子
a pair of gold bracelets for the child.
买了个大金镯子呢
Does the wound
那这伤口
have anything to do with her?
跟她有关系吗
She didn't mean to.
她也是好心
Sorry. Haowen.
对不住了啊 浩文
Mengxin suffered.
又让心心遭罪了
Sorry to bother you.
也给你添麻烦了
In fact,
我大姑姐那个人吧
she is quite good.
其实挺好的
But she just
但是她就是
likes
就是喜欢
living in
生活在自己的
her own world.
那个世界里头
She took care of me
我坐月子的时候
when I was in Postpartum Confinement.
就是她照顾的
So I can understand you.
我特别能够感同身受
It's hard to say, you know.
就没法说 你知道吧
Meng'an.
姐姐姐 我
I really feel it.
我真的感受到了
Be patient.
挺挺吧
Everything will pass.
挺挺就过去了
Meng'an.
姐
En...
那个
The wound of Mengxin is cracked.
心心这不是伤口裂了吗
So she is very upset
心情很烦躁
and doesn't want to see anyone.
谁都不想见
Even me?
连我都不想见啦
She dare not.
那她哪儿敢呢
She is really asleep.
真的是睡了
Well.
那行
Then I won't go in.
那我就不进去了
What is important now
现在
is to ensure her physical
重要的是保证她的
and mental pleasure.
身心愉悦
As long as she is happy,
只要她高兴了
we will be relieved.
咱们也就都轻省了
Yeah.
是是是 姐 真的
Mengxin suffered this time.
心心这次遭这罪
I feel terrible.
我心里这不得劲
She was wheeled from
这从产房
the delivery room to the operating room.
给推到手术室去
She suffered too much.
这哪儿是人遭的罪啊
I wish I could
我恨不得替她
bear all this for her.
挨这一刀去
You are hating me.
你这是也记恨我呢
How dare I?
这我哪儿敢呢 姐
You are right.
您说得对
We need to keep her and baby safe.
咱不能一尸两命
Well.
行吧
Take care of Mengxin.
那你照顾心心吧
I will go back.
我就回去了
Go back?
回去啊
Go back.
回吧 回吧
See you, Meng'an.
您慢点啊 姐
Call me if you need anything.
有事给我打电话
Well.
好好好
Our sister was here. I kicked her out
姐来了 我给她轰走了
and wouldn't let her in.
不让她进来
Let you...
让你安
Really?
是吗
Meng'an.
姐
Good for you.
你现在可以啊
I'm sorry.
对不起 姐
I was wrong.
我错了 姐
Go and reflect.
那你去哪儿反省会儿啊
OK.
好嘞
I'll watch at the door.
我到门口守着去
Honey.
老婆
I won't let anyone
我再也不让任何人
in again.
进来了
Get out, both of you.
都出去
You first.
你先出去
OK.
好嘞
You don't want to see me?
不想见我
Are you still angry?
还生气呢
No gifts?
空着手就来了
I came as soon as
我这不收到信
I heard
说你伤口裂开了
your wound had split.
就 没来得及去买吗
So I didn't have time to buy it.
就惦记你
Your elder sister knows
你大姑姐还知道
to bring gold bracelets.
带个金镯子
I'll buy it for you now.
那我现在去给你买点啊
OK.
去吧
Don't come back.
去了就别回来
Mengxin.
心心
Don't be angry.
你也别生气了
Your brother-in-law and I
我跟你姐夫
didn't know she was coming.
真的不知道他大姐要来
But once we know,
但凡知道了
we can't let her come by herself.
也不可能让她自己来
You haven't seen each other
你想你们都多长时间
for a long time.
没见了
The last time was
上次还是
when I was in Postpartum Confinement.
我坐月子的时候见的吧
If she is coming,
那 来肯定也是
we will come with her.
我们带着她来
I didn't expect her
没想到大姐她
to be so enthusiastic.
这么热情啊
And
而且
you know
他大姐那个人你也知道
she's not a bad person.
她不是个坏人
I'm sure
就是
she didn't know
她肯定不知道
this would happen.
会造成这样的后果的
But if she knows,
但凡知道了
she can't be like this.
也不可能是这样的
Right?
是吧
I'm what?
怎么样了
It's cracked.
不是 裂开了吗
What?
哪儿裂开了
Wound.
刀口啊
Because of what?
为什么会有刀口啊
Caesarean section.
剖腹产哪
Who decided?
谁让我剖腹产的
Doctor.
大夫呀
Who signed it?
谁签的字
Jia Haowen.
贾浩文啊
Who forced him?
谁逼他签的字
You mean
这是
me?
根了吗
Get out.
出去
I don't want to see you.
我不想看到你 你出去
Don't cry.
别哭 别哭
Don't touch me.
别碰我
No.
不
Take it easy.
那那 你别激动
Look.
你看
A foregone conclusion.
反正它切也切了
I mean,
不是 我的意思是说
if the doctor can
但凡大夫能让你
give you a side cut,
侧切的话
he won't...
也不会在你肚子上
Get out.
你出去
I...
我我我
Well.
行
I'll go.
我走
Don't cry.
你就别哭了
En...
那个
If you are in a bad mood,
心情不好的话
you can importune.
你就作他们
Do as you please.
使劲作
Anyway...
反正
Importune?
谁作了
No. No.
没作 没作
They don't understand you.
是他们都不理解
Importune?
我是作吗
No. No.
不是作
Absolutely not.
绝对没有作
I believe you.
姐相信你
I am in pain.
我是疼
In pain.
疼
I know.
姐知道疼
Who made me hurt?
谁让我疼的
Get out.
你出去 出去
I don't want to see you.
我不想看到你
I'm leaving. I'm leaving. I'm leaving.
我走 我走 我走
Don't come here again.
以后也别再来
Because of the wound?
就因为一个刀口啊
Not enough, right?
还不够是吧
No. No.
够了 够了
No.
够了
I'm leaving. I'm leaving.
我走 我走
Call me
那你想着
if you need anything.
有事给我打电话
Get out.
走
Well.
走 走
Meng'an.
姐
Why did you come out so soon?
你咋这么快也出来啦
I'd like to stay longer.
我倒是想多待会儿呢
Do you think it's wrong for me
你觉得我让她
to let her have a caesarean section?
剖腹产这事有错吗
No. You are right.
没错 姐 当然没错
Did I make you sign it?
那是我逼你签的字吗
With your knowledge of her,
你觉得以你对她的了解
how long will she forgive me?
这事她多长时间能过去
It depends on her mood.
这她得看心情了
Last time she knew she was pregnant,
上次知道自己怀孕了
she didn't talk to me for three months.
仨月都没搭理我
So it will take
那我这一刀
half a year this time anyway.
怎么也得半年了
Haowen.
浩文啊
I'm counting on you.
全靠你了啊
Come on.
来 来 来
Well.
好 好
Be careful.
慢点
Good.
漂亮
I want to play on the swing.
我要玩秋千
Together.
玩双玩呗
Come on. One, two, three.
来 一二三
Zhenzhen. What are you doing?
真真 干什么呢
We are playing Frisbee.
我们在玩飞盘呢
Good.
真好
Where's your sister?
姐姐呢
Come on.
姐姐 快过来
Dad.
爸爸
Dad. Where are you?
爸爸 你在哪儿呢
I just got back from a business trip.
我啊 我这刚出差回来
Look.
你看
I'm still in the car.
是在路上跑着呢还
I miss you guys.
爸爸又想你们了
So I want to see you now.
给你们打个视频啊
Dad, I miss you, too.
爸爸我也想你了
I'm going to play.
我先去玩啦
Dad, I'm telling you,
爸爸 我跟你说
she can play Frisbee
姐姐抛飞盘
really well.
抛得可厉害啦
High and far.
又高又远
I can't catch it.
我都接不住
Look.
你看
Dad, I want to play Frisbee.
爸爸 我要抛飞盘了
I'll hang up.
我先挂了哈
OK.
好嘞好嘞
Be safe.
注意安全啊
I'm telling you,
我跟你说啊
the edge of Frisbee
那个 那个飞盘
is particularly hard.
那个边特别硬
Watch your head.
别打着头
Don't just
还有就是那个
look at the sky
别光看着天上
to catch it.
准备接飞盘
Watch your step.
你看着点脚底下
Don't trip.
别绊倒了
Watch
别到时候那个就
yourself.
顾头不顾屁股的
Okay, bye, dad.
好 再见爸爸
Well.
行行行
Have fun.
好好好
Aunt, let's have dinner.
大姑 快点开饭呗
I'm hungry.
我饿了
Right away.
马上就得
What to cook?
做什么呢 姐
You will know in a moment.
一会儿就知道了
Dad.
爸
What's the matter?
怎么了
The sharpness of a sword is honed...
宝剑锋从
The fragrance of plum blossoms...
梅花香
I did it
我立这块牌子
just to make you study hard
就是为了让你努力学习
and get into a key high school.
考入重点高中
Come on.
加油
Dinner will be served soon.
马上就开饭了
Dad.
爸
When will she leave?
我大姑什么时候走啊
In fact, it doesn't
其实这牌子挂在这儿
affect your daily life.
也不影响你日常活动啊
Dad.
爸
Do your homework.
做功课
Today I talk about four categories.
今天呢 主要讲四大类
I've been investigating
我 最近在调研
the liabilities of a real estate company
一家地产公司的
recently.
负债情况
Look.
看一下
Here are some information
这是我收集到的
I have collected.
一些资料
Some public
都是明面公开的
data.
一些数据
Where can I
您觉得
collect more
还有哪些地方可以
comprehensive information?
收集到更全面的信息呢
Some are hidden.
还有一些是隐藏的
You can know
你可以从债务的结构中
the source of debt,
去了解一下
the amount of bank financing
这些债务是怎么来的
and other financing
它的银行融资有多少
from the structure of debt.
其他融资有多少
They can all
这些信息呢
be retrieved
都可以在这些项目中
and consulted
去调取
in these projects.
查阅
That will give you a more accurate
可以让你对这家公司呢
understanding of this company.
有着更准确地了解
Got it. Thank you.
知道了 谢谢老师啊
You're welcome.
不客气
Please look at
你再帮我看一下
these data for me.
还有这些数据
Come on. One more.
来 再来一个
How's it going?
怎么样
Good.
漂亮
Go.
走
Catch it.
接好
Throw it back.
好 扔回来
Your dad's back.
爸爸回来了 来
Dad.
爸爸
Wanwan. Zhenzhen.
婉婉 真真
I miss you guys.
想死我了
Kiss you.
亲一下
Look.
看看 看看
Gifts for you.
爸爸买什么了
A new skirt for each of you.
每人一条新裙子
A father rabbit.
还有一个兔子爸爸
A mother rabbit.
兔子妈妈
Who wants?
谁要
I want mother rabbit.
我是兔子妈妈
Mother rabbit.
你要兔子妈妈
Father rabbit.
兔子爸爸
Dad.
对了 爸爸
Let's play together.
我们一起玩吧
He is really
医生叔叔玩飞盘
good at Frisbee.
可厉害了
We can form a team.
咱们可以组 组个队
Your dad's back.
爸爸回来了
So I'm leaving.
叔叔就下班了啊
Take it.
来 拿着
I'm leaving.
走了
Bye.
拜拜
Bye, uncle.
医生叔叔 再见
Dad.
爸爸
Let's play Frisbee together.
我们一起玩飞盘吧
Let's play together.
我们一起玩吧
Come here.
来 上这边玩来
Come.
来
Hello, Mr. Yu.
于先生好
Hello.
您好 您好
We don't play Frisbee.
咱 咱不玩飞盘好吧
Right?
好吧
How boring.
老玩飞盘多没意思呀
I'll tell you a story
我给你们讲一个
about father rabbit
兔子爸爸
and mother rabbit.
跟兔子妈妈的故事
Mother rabbit is so beautiful.
兔子妈妈好漂亮啊
Father rabbit
这个兔子爸爸呀
loves mother rabbit very much.
特别爱兔子妈妈
Sometimes
然后呢 有的时候吧
they fight.
他们也会吵架
Right?
是不是
Then
然后呢
they broke up.
他们俩就不好了
Right?
是吧 就不好了
But
但是呢
they will always be a family.
他们俩永远是一家人
Come on.
来
Eat eggs.
吃鸡蛋
It is nutritious.
鸡蛋有营养
Don't bite chopsticks.
不要咬筷子
That's impolite.
不文明
Behave well.
吃饭就要有吃饭的规矩
Aunt.
大姑
They are all vegetarian dishes.
你这饭做得也太素了吧
Not even a meat dish.
连个肉菜都没有
No.
怎么没肉菜啊
It is a meat dish.
这不是肉菜吗
It's shredded pork.
这是肉丝
But it is also meat.
肉丝也是肉啊
Eat it.
吃吧
Just a little meat.
就这么点肉
It is not a meat dish
这在我们家
in our family.
这顶多算个荤菜
I want to eat meat dishes.
我要吃的是肉菜
Large meatball.
什么狮子头啊
Dongpo's braised pork.
东坡肉啊
Shank.
肘子
Fried chicken.
炸鸡
Fish is also okay.
你烧个鱼也行呀
Except fish,
除了鱼
what you just said
你刚才说的那些
is unhealthy food.
都是不健康食品
These are all
你看大姑做的这些
health foods that I make.
这都是养生食品 懂吗
I don't need to keep fit,
我不需要养生
I have to grow up.
我得长身体
I need nutrition.
我需要营养
Yunjie.
云阶
Let it be.
今天就这样
I will buy you
明天
ready-made food tomorrow.
爸给你买现成的
You are not allowed.
不许买
Look.
你看看
She got pimples on her face
她脸上都长痘了
from eating meat.
这就是吃肉吃的
She has a phlegm-dampness constitution.
痰湿体质
You should be more vegetarian.
你得多吃素
Such as yam.
像这个山药啊 什么的
It can help you get rid of dampness.
排湿 你可以多吃
Eat it.
快吃
Forget it.
算了
Let it be.
凑合吃得了
Dad, bring me
爸 你把那个腐乳罐
the fermented bean curd.
拿给我
Don't eat too much salt.
不要吃太多的盐
This kind of pickled food
以后在咱们家
is not allowed in our home
不允许出现这种
in the future,
腌制食品
okay?
懂吗
Future?
以后
How are your grades?
你考试怎么样啊
Where do you rank in your class?
排名第几啊 在班上
I'm full.
我吃饱了
I'll do my homework.
写作业去
Yunjie. What are you doing?
你干吗呢 云阶
You
你看 你看你
spoil her too much.
把孩子惯的
She didn't behave well.
一点规矩都没有
Jing.
姐
Let's eat.
吃饭 吃饭
En...
不是
Whatever her ranking,
她再考第几名
she must eat meat.
她也得吃点肉啊
I did it for her own good.
我这不是为了她好吗
Students should be learning-oriented.
学生就要以学习为本哪
We don't talk about studying
我们家吃饭的时候
when we eat at home.
不说学习
I have at least
我做饭的时候
one meat dish
至少每一顿
when I cook.
要有一个纯肉的菜
En...
这
Yunjie. Meng'an.
云阶 梦安
They are not
她们也不是
vegetarians.
撞钟吃素的呀
Besides,
再说了
Meng'an is pregnant now.
梦安现在怀着孕
Yunjie is growing up.
云阶长身体呢
They need nutrition.
要补营养
Okay, I get it.
好了 我知道了
There will be
从明天开始
a meat dish every day from tomorrow,
每天有一个纯肉菜
okay?
行了吧
I'll cook
以后做饭的事
later.
还是我来吧
No.
那不行
I am idle,
我自己闲着
but I let you cook.
我让我弟弟干活
I can't do it.
不行
It's okay.
那怎么不行啊
I have been cooking
这 我家做饭
at home.
就是我做的呀
It's normal.
很正常嘛
Look.
你看你 你看你
I treated you
你小时候
like an emperor
这我把你当小皇帝
when you were a child.
一样伺候
But now you
你说你长大了到人家
are serving others.
你给人当长工你
You shouldn't say that.
姐 这话就很难听了
I'm fine.
我怎么样了
I just cook.
我做点事怎么了
Why do you still have such
你怎么还有这种
feudal and backward ideas?
这种封建落后的思想呢
You are
我怎么封建
talking nonsense.
怎么落后
It's a fact.
这不事实吗
I can't beat you.
行 我说不过你
Eat.
吃饭
Yeah.
就是嘛
You are verbose.
吃个饭还啰哩啰嗦的
Don't talk.
不许说话啊
Did I cook well?
姐饭做得好吃吗
What brings you here?
你怎么来了
I just got back from a business trip.
我出差刚回来
I miss my children.
我想孩子了
Did you see them?
见着了吗
They get along well with your neighbor.
跟你那邻居玩挺好啊
Then you can leave.
见着了还不走
What did you do?
你这么晚干吗去了
Have a class.
我上课
Chen Wanzhen.
陈婉真 我告诉你
You said
当初你说
you would take care of the children,
你愿意照顾孩子
so I gave you custody
我才把孩子的抚养权
of them.
交给了你
I hope
我是希望
their lives
孩子的生活
will not change.
不要有什么变化
You take them
她们上学放学
to and from school as usual.
照样是妈妈接 妈妈送
After school,
放了学之后
you accompany them to do their homework.
有妈妈陪她们写作业
You cook
孩子想吃什么好吃的
whatever they want to eat.
有妈妈给做
You sleep
晚上睡觉的时候
with them.
妈妈给搂着
Why?
因为什么
We are not together.
因为咱俩不在一块儿
Right?
对吧
I don't want their lives
我不希望孩子的生活
to change much.
有太大的变化
But what about you?
可是你呢
You want to be a career woman, right?
你想当事业女性 对吧
Well.
好
I support you.
我支持你当事业女性
I hope you are well.
我也希望你好
But you
但是你做这事业女性
can't sacrifice
你不能拿孩子的童年
their childhood.
作为牺牲吧
Yu Hai.
于海
You have gone too far.
你有点上纲上线了啊
En...
不是
As a mother,
你就说你作为一个母亲
how can you give your
你能把自己的孩子
two girls
而且是小女孩
to such
交给这么
a strange man?
一个陌生男人吗
You think this is appropriate?
你觉得你这样妥当吗
Now the society is so complicated.
你现在社会上多乱哪
How unpredictable people are.
人心多叵测啊
Don't you know?
你难道你不知道吗
If you can
如果说
give them to someone else
是你说的这个照顾
to take care of,
是交给别人来照顾
so can I.
那我也可以啊
Right?
对吧
I can hire some nannies
我可以雇几个人
to take care of them
让我父亲 我母亲
with my parents, right?
一块儿照顾孩子 对吧
You
反正你 就这么着
left our daughters
就把自己的女儿
in the care of a stranger.
交给一个陌生人去照顾
As their father,
我作为父亲
I don't agree.
这我不答应
If I
你别让我再发现
find it again,
再发现一次
I'll see you in court.
咱就法院见
Not you.
我没说你
Don't rush me.
别催了
I'm on my way.
我在路上呢
Jing.
姐
I thought about it all day.
我啊 琢磨了一天了
I have something to discuss with you.
有件事想跟你商量商量
In a few days, I want to go back to
我想过两天回趟老家
our hometown
给咱爸
to visit our father's grave.
上上坟 扫扫墓
Let's go together.
咱一块儿去啊
What do you mean?
你什么意思啊
Nothing.
我没什么意思啊
Just homesick.
就是想家了嘛
I haven't been back for a long time.
好久都没回去了
I see.
我明白了
It's Xu Meng'an who asked you
是许梦安让你出面
to kick me back, right?
撵我回去的吧
No.
不是
She doesn't know.
梦安不知道
It is I who want to discuss with you.
是我跟你商量商量
Look.
你看 你看
I know it's not her.
我就说不是梦安吧
She wants me
梦安还总跟我说 姐
to stay a few more days.
你多住些日子
Why do you send me back?
那你凭什么撵我回去
Look.
你 你看
There you are.
你来了
You saw Meng'an,
你也见着梦安了
my father-in-law
也见着我老丈人了
and Mengxin.
梦心你也见着了
You have seen them all.
这一圈的人你都见着了
You've done everything you need to do.
礼数你也到了
You should be at ease.
心里 是不是就踏实了
You go back, I won't.
要回你回吧 我不回
I have to take care of Meng'an.
我还得照顾梦安呢
I'll do it.
梦安有我照顾就行了
Well.
你这样的
Come back
等着梦安生的时候啊
when she gives birth.
你再来
Maybe we will
没准那会儿啊
move to a new home then.
我们也搬了大家了
Right?
是吧
The conditions
这个 现在你看这条件
are not good now.
不好
Li Lin.
李临
I am your sister.
我还是不是你亲姐姐
You treat me like
你拿我当什么了
an outsider?
外人吗
No.
我没有啊
I...
我 我
Stop it.
你什么没有
Such a ungrateful person.
你就是个白眼狼
You forget
你忘了 我当时
how I
小时候
raised you
咱们俩怎么相依为命
when we were children.
把你带大的吗
Our mother died early.
咱妈走得早
Our father run the clinic alone.
咱爸一个人操持着医馆
I took care of everything
家里大事小事
in our family.
都扔到我一个人头上
Was that easy for me?
我容易吗
I washed clothes,
我还得给你洗衣服
cooked meals
给你做饭
and attended your parents' meeting.
我还得给你开家长会
You fought with someone else,
你跟别人打架了
and I would fight for you.
我还得替你去打架
Well.
是
I didn't worry about your study.
你学习上没有让我操心
But I took care of everything else.
但是你吃喝拉撒谁管
I
我
was not much older than you.
当时比你大不了几岁
I was a child, too.
我也是个孩子
Nobody cares about me.
谁管我了
Right?
是吧
You have your own family now.
你现在有自己的小家了
You forget
你忘了你当时
how you grew up.
是怎么长大的
You kick me
你就把你亲姐姐
out.
往出撵呀
Well.
好了 好了
Take it easy.
不激动 不激动
I shouldn't have said it.
我就不该说
Sorry.
我错了
Jing.
姐
I am sorry.
对不起啊
Just forget I ever said that.
你就当我没说过这话
OK?
行吗
En...
这这这
Here you are.
给你
You don't know why
我为什么突然来你家
I suddenly came to your home?
你心里没点数吗
So what do you
姐 你说的这 数是
mean?
几个数啊
Let me ask you,
我问你
after Meng'an is pregnant,
你知道梦安怀二胎以后
do you want to have it or not?
你们是想要还是不想要
Yes, of course.
那当然是想要啊
Meng'an, too?
梦安也想要吗
Yeah.
梦安也想要啊
You lied to me.
你骗人
Lanxiang told me
兰香跟我说了
you wanted to
你们当时就想
abort the baby at that time.
把孩子打掉
Right?
对吗
Don't listen to Lanxiang.
你不要听兰香的
She talks nonsense.
见风就是雨的 她瞎说
We know better than she does.
我们的事不比她清楚啊
Well.
不是 是这么回事
Meng'an has threatened abortion.
梦安不是有先兆流产吗
So we didn't want to tell anyone
那头三个月我们不想说
for the first three months.
是吧
We are tight-lipped.
口风得紧
We don't want to be happy
免得到时候
for nothing.
空欢喜一场
Right?
对不对
You wanted children at that time.
那你们当时是想要的
Yeah.
对啊
Well.
我就说嘛
I told Meng'an about the second child.
我跟梦安说过二胎的事
I didn't expect
没想到
her to take it to heart.
她还往心里去了
Yeah.
对
Well.
那好了 行了
You can rest assured.
这 这下你放心了吧
Yeah.
放心了 放心了
OK.
放心了 放心了啊
Jing.
姐
Let's
我们
choose a good day.
择个良辰吉日的
The big bed at home
家里的大床
is more comfortable than the small bed.
不比这小板床舒服
Let me tell you,
我跟你说啊
don't worry about me.
你不要操心我的问题
I can sleep on the ground.
我睡在地铺上都可以
Meng'an is in early stages of pregnancy
梦安现在是孕早期
and may have miscarriage at any time.
随时有可能流产
Once we've ensured the pregnancy is stable
等梦安胎保住了
and her belly has grown,
肚子也大了
that's when I'll consider
我那个时候
whether to stay or go.
再商量走不走
OK?
好不好
You can't drink it.
不能喝
Give it to me.
给我
The coke
这种刚从冰箱
just taken out of the refrigerator
拿出来的可乐
can't be drunk.
不能喝
It's unhealthy, you know?
不健康 知道吗
Have you finished your homework?
作业写完了吗
Yeah.
写完了
Really?
作业真写完啦
Or what?
那不然呢
Need fresh air
我要出去透透气
I will accompany you.
爸陪你
Dad, come on.
爸
Come back early.
那早点回来啊
Where can I get some air?
我上哪儿透气呢
Go back to my room.
回屋吧
So cool.
太爽了
I don't need wellness,
我不要养生
I want joy.
我要快乐
What are you gonna do now?
那你这以后怎么办呀
Your aunt won't leave?
你大姑还就不走了
My mother is annoying enough.
本来我妈就够烦的了
But my aunt
结果再来个大姑
is more annoying than my mother.
比我妈烦十倍
Fifteen times
不
as much as my mother.
十五倍
Quite accurate.
你这还挺精确呀
He Lu, let me ask you a question.
何璐 我问你个问题啊
Was it planned or accidental
你妈生你弟
that your mother
是计划好的
gave birth to your brother?
还是意外的呀
Of course, it was planned.
当然是计划好的呀
They are all premeditated.
他们都是有预谋的
They taught us
这些大人
not to lie
天天都说不让我们撒谎
but to be honest.
要诚实
But
结果呢
they lie to
他们自己为了达到目的
get what
还不是什么谎话
they want.
都说得出来
No.
不行
I need another drink.
我得再来一杯
One more drink.
再来一杯
Here I am.
来了
Mr. Yu.
于总
Here is your Frisbee.
这是您要的飞盘
I brought it for you.
我帮您送来了
En...
那个
Do you know
这 这 这东西
how to play it?
你知道怎么玩吗
It usually needs
这个 一般都要
more than two people.
两个人以上玩
Throw it and catch it.
就是扔出去 然后接住
On the Internet, I saw people holding it
就 我上网一看都是
to interact with dogs.
这小狗跟人一块儿玩的
Dogs can.
小狗能玩
So can you.
你也能玩
OK.
好嘞
Thank you.
辛苦你啊
Good night. Mr. Yu.
早点休息 于总